<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE dita PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Composite//EN" "ditabase.dtd">
<dita><concept id="DAFFARS_5346_311">
      <title><ph props="autonumber">5346.311</ph> Higher-Level Contract Quality Requirement.</title>
      <conbody>

        <p>Agencies shall establish procedures for determining when
higher-level contract quality requirements are necessary, for
determining the risk (both the likelihood and the impact) of
nonconformance, and for advising the contracting officer about
which higher-level standards should be applied and included in the
solicitation and contract. Requiring compliance with higher-level
quality standards is necessary in solicitations and contracts for
complex or critical items (see FAR <xref format="html" href="https://www.acquisition.gov/far/part-46#FAR_46_204" scope="external">46.203</xref>)
or when the technical requirements of the contract require -</p>
        <p>(1) Control of such things as design, work operations,
in-process controls, testing and inspection; or</p>
        <p>(2) Attention to such factors as organization, planning, work
instructions, documentation control, and advanced metrology,</p>
        <p>(a) The Contractor shall comply with the higher-level quality
standard(s) listed below.</p>
        <p>___________________________[Contracting Officer shall insert the
title, number (if any), date, and tailoring (if any) of the
higher-level quality standards.]</p>
        <p>(b) The Contractor shall include applicable requirements of the
higher-level quality standard(s) listed in paragraph (a) of this
clause and the requirement to flow down such standards, as
applicable, to lower-tier subcontracts, in-</p>

        <p>(1) Any subcontract for critical and complex items (see FAR <xref format="html" href="https://www.acquisition.gov/far/46.203" scope="external">46.203</xref>(b) and
(c)); or</p>
        <p>(2) When the technical requirements of a subcontract
require-</p>
        <p>(i) Control of such things as design, work operations,
in-process control, testing, and inspection; or</p>
        <p>(ii) Attention to such factors as organization, planning, work
instructions, documentation control, and advanced metrology.</p>
        <p>(c) See FAR <xref format="html" href="https://www.acquisition.gov/far/46.311" scope="external">46.311</xref>
        </p>
      </conbody>
    </concept></dita>